CHRIS ELIAS

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER / UI DESIGNER

(708) 860-9914 chris@chriselias.com chriselias.com @chriselias

I am a Chicago based Full Stack Web Developer / UI designer with over 10 years of experience developing and designing, modern websites and javascript applications with a strong background in team leadership, product development and client support.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript ES5/67 CSS3, SASS, Less, and Bootstrap Azure Cloud Services

Node JS / Express Mobile and Responsive Design Webpack, Grunt, and Gulp

AngularJS / 2+ Wordpress Theme Development UI Design

ReactJS MongoDB Sketch / Adobe Creative Suite

REST API Development Firebase Wireframing and App Prototype

REST API Development Firebase Wireframing and App Prototyping Ionic Mobile Framework PHP Search Engine Optimization

JQuery MySQL Email Marketing

HTML5 AWS (EC2, S3, and RDS) Salesforce Customization

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CO-FOUNDER, VP OF PRODUCT AND TECHNOLOGY

MY LOCAL BEACON | FEBRUARY 2014 - PRESENT

Directs all planning, design, development, and support for digital marketing products and services. Manages team of developers, designers, and support staff to implement new products and features.

- Designed and developed web application using Angular, Node JS, and MSSql which serves as:
 - Internal CRM and provisioning tool to activate new client services
 - Client Facing access of Patient Beacon services (Review Generation, SEO, Reputation and Website Management)
 - Client Dashboard and Reporting pulling in 3rd-party APIs from Google and Bright Local
- Designed and developed hybrid mobile app in lonic framework for Medical practices to communicate and market directly to clients and patients through location and scheduled push notifications
- Architected scalable and custom Wordpress website solution on AWS integrated into Patient Beacon web application
- Implemented SEO program for SMB clients across several verticals
- Directs the team through a process-driven methodology to ensure project goals, QA standards, documentation and internal best-practices are routinely followed

LEAD WEB ENGINEER

LEXTECH MOBILE | AUGUST 2013 - FEBRUARY 2014

Team lead role responsible for development and delivery of large scale custom Angular.js applications and websites using the latest web and database technologies.

- Managed team of full stack developers working on custom Angular web applications
- Provided estimates for new projects and delivered within specific time frames
- Coordinated with QA departments to resolve issues with releases and test environments
- Planned project deliveries using the Scrum methodology

DIRECTOR OF WEB INNOVATION

OFFICITE | FEBRUARY 2009 - AUGUST 2013

Led the Product Development team of developers and designers in the design, architecture, development and maintenance of Officite's web applications and client websites.

- Oversaw team of Front-End Web Developers in custom development of client facing Javascript applications, HTML5 Web templates, and Wordpress websites
- Drove product web development and release strategy
- Managed company website and online marketing programs
- Preformed annual employee reviews to mentor employee progress and develop growth opportunities
- Identified team strengths and weaknesses. Engage in mentoring, establish training plans and staffing recommendations that align the team's skill set to business needs and technical innovations

CLIENT SERVICES MANAGER

OFFICITE | DECEMBER 2004 - APRIL 2009

Managed the development and production of dynamic websites for Offcite's expansive online medical marketing program. Led team in building new sites, updating existing sites, and providing technical support for a client base of 6000+.

- Managed Customer Support Team responsible for all maintenance and client communication
- Hired and trained employees
- Designed and coded HTML / CSS markup for custom web templates and client sites
- Managed the design and distribution for corporate email marketing program
- Developed and maintained internal technical knowledge base for support and development teams
- Created and implemented SEO / PPC product

WEB DEVELOPER

OFFICITE | MARCH 2004 - DECEMBER 2004

Provided one-on-one support and consulted clients on all aspects of website development, online marketing and best practices.

- Worked with clients to customize and maintain website content with HTML, CSS, and Javascript
- Provided technical support by troubleshooting website and email issues with clients
- Developed optimal search strategies and managed Google AdWords Campaigns

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT CHICAGO - CHICAGO, IL

B.F.A. Electronic Media - Distinction in Computer Graphics, Photography and Film, May 2003